Hunter Piggot

Colorado Springs, Colorado | (719)432-8466 | hunterpiggot@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/hunter-piggot/ | github.com/hunterpiggot

SUMMARY

As a Full Stack Software Engineer with 2 years of experience, instrumental in the development and maintenance of three web applications. Current skill sets include React, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, CSS, and HTML. Continuously showing a track record of delivering software solutions with a near 100% on-time completion rate and enhancing application performance across projects. In addition to professional work, currently participating in the Caltech Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning Bootcamp that started in 2023.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

February 2022 – June 2023

React Developer, Cazton - Remote

- Developed two healthcare web portal front ends from scratch using React, TypeScript, Google Cloud Platform, and Python, leading many parts of the application in data management for a range of medical professionals.
- Implemented best practices while managing sensitive, medical, and personal data and implemented local formatting being accessed across over 30 different countries.
- Exercised Agile Development methodology, collaborating with a diverse team of 25 front-end, back-end, and UI/UX developers, and completed twice the assigned workload, contributing to the team's overall progress.
- Initiated a back-end architectural redesign for data aggregation, leading to a 300% increase in application performance and higher user satisfaction. Collaborated with cross-functional teams to accomplish this improvement.

July 2021 - February 2022

Full-Stack Developer, JKP Group - Colorado Springs, Colorado

- Pioneered a front-end application in React with three pages that allowed users to calculate mortgage payments, see gross equity value, and have a comprehensive first-time home buyer guide.
- Incorporated three REST APIs getting home analytics and property value to create a better, easier user experience.
- Created a robust back-end system leveraging Python and Flask that stores and manages property analytics while engaging with the client to understand specific needs, resulting in a tailored solution that enhanced data-driven decision-making.
- Communicated with the company owner to create and implement all designs and functionalities within the application and existing website.

ADDITIONAL ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Finished a multitude of software development projects with almost perfect on-time completion rate, showcasing outstanding coding abilities and exemplary skill in task prioritization.
- Engaged in daily team meetings, code reviews, and brainstorming sessions to drive project success and contribute to a positive team environment.
- Continuously sought opportunities for professional growth and skill development, attending workshops, webinars, and conferences related to web development and emerging technologies.
- Mentored and coordinated comprehensive coaching to a group of five individuals with no prior coding experience, guiding through the process of acquiring essential programming skills, leading to securing employment in the technology industry.

EDUCATION	SKILLS Flask		Git
	React	AJAX, AXIOS	GitHub
2020-2021	JavaScript	CSS	Bitbucket
Springboard Full Stack Dev.	TypeScript	HTML	Jenkins
Bootcamp	Python	Vite	Agile
2019-2020	.NET	Chart.js	JAMA Cloud
Arizona State University -	C#	PostgreSQL	Responsive Design
Computer Science	GraphQL	FastAPI	Accessible Design
20pata. 20.0.100	jQuery	Tailwind Css	Adobe Photoshop